<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<local_library_data>
  <books>
    <book>
      <title>A Dance with Dragons</title>
      <author>George Martin</author>
      <summary>
        A Dance with Dragons picks up where A Storm of Swords leaves off and runs simultaneously with events in A Feast
        for Crows. The War of the Five Kings seems to be winding down. In the north, King Stannis Baratheon has
        installed himself at the Wall and vowed to win the support of the northmen to continue his struggle to claim
        the Iron Throne, although this is complicated by the fact that much of the west coast is under occupation by
        the ironborn. On the Wall itself Jon Snow has been elected the 998th Lord Commander of the Night's Watch, but
        has enemies both in the Watch and beyond the Wall. Tyrion Lannister has been taken by ship across the narrow
        sea to Pentos, but his eventual goals are unknown even to him. On Slaver's Bay, Daenerys Targaryen has
        conquered the city of Meereen, and has decided to stay and rule the city, honing her skills of leadership
        which will be needed when she travels on to Westeros. Daenerys's presence is now known to many in Westeros,
        and from the Iron Islands and Dorne, from Oldtown and the Free Cities, emissaries are on their way to find her
        and use her cause for their own ends...
      </summary>
      <isbn>9780553801477</isbn>
      <genre>Epic Fantasy</genre>
      <language>English</language>
    </book>

    <book>
      <title>A Feast for Crows</title>
      <author>George Martin</author>
      <summary>
        A Feast for Crows picks up the tale where A Storm of Swords leaves off and runs simultaneously with events in
        the following novel, A Dance with Dragons. The War of the Five Kings seems to be winding down. Robb Stark,
        Joffrey Baratheon, Renly Baratheon, and Balon Greyjoy are dead. King Stannis Baratheon has fled to the Wall,
        where Jon Snow has become Lord Commander. King Tommen Baratheon, Joffrey's eight-year-old brother, now rules
        in King's Landing under the watchful eye of his mother, the Queen Regent Cersei Lannister. Lord Tywin
        Lannister is dead, murdered by his son Tyrion in his flight from the city. Sansa Stark is in hiding in the
        Vale, protected by Petyr Baelish who has murdered his wife Lysa Arryn and named himself Protector of the Vale
        and guardian of eight-year-old Lord Robert Arryn.
      </summary>
      <isbn>0553801503</isbn>
      <genre>Epic Fantasy</genre>
      <language>English</language>
    </book>

    <book>
      <title>A Game of Thrones</title>
      <author>George Martin</author>
      <summary>
        A Game of Thrones is set in the Seven Kingdoms of Westeros, a land reminiscent of Medieval Europe. In Westeros
        the seasons last for years, sometimes decades, at a time. Fifteen years prior to the novel, the Seven Kingdoms
        were torn apart by a civil war, known alternately as "Robert's Rebellion" and the "War of the Usurper." Prince
        Rhaegar Targaryen kidnapped Lyanna Stark, arousing the ire of her family and of her betrothed, Lord Robert
        Baratheon (the war's titular rebel). The Mad King, Aerys II Targaryen, had Lyanna's father and eldest brother
        executed when they demanded her safe return. Her second brother, Eddard, joined his boyhood friend Robert
        Baratheon and Jon Arryn, with whom they had been fostered as children, in declaring war against the ruling
        Targaryen dynasty, securing the allegiances of House Tully and House Arryn through a network of dynastic
        marriages (Lord Eddard to Catelyn Tully and Lord Arryn to Lysa Tully). The powerful House Tyrell continued to
        support the King, but House Lannister and House Martell both stalled due to insults against their houses by
        the Targaryens. The civil war climaxed with the Battle of the Trident, when Prince Rhaegar was killed in
        battle by Robert Baratheon. The Lannisters finally agreed to support King Aerys, but then brutally turned
        against him, sacking the capital at King's Landing. Jaime Lannister of the Kingsguard betrayed and murdered
        King Aerys and House Lannister swore loyalty to Robert Baratheon. The Tyrells and remaining royalists
        surrendered and Robert Baratheon was declared King of the Seven Kingdoms. Unfortunately, during the war,
        Lyanna Stark had died, apparently of illness shortly after her brother captured the fortress where she'd been
        held captive; Robert Baratheon instead married Cersei Lannister to cement the alliance with her House. Despite
        Robert's victory, the Mad King's younger son Viserys and only daughter Daenerys were taken to safety across
        the sea by loyal retainers. After the war House Martell chose a path of isolation, since Prince Doran's sister
        Elia Martell (Prince Rhaegar's wife) and her young children had been killed by knights sworn to House
        Lannister during the storming of the capital. Six years later, King Robert proved his resolve by defeating a
        rebellion by Lord Balon Greyjoy of the Iron Islands. Balon's two eldest sons were killed and his youngest son,
        Theon, was given to the care of Eddard Stark as a ward.
      </summary>
      <isbn>0553103547</isbn>
      <genre>Epic Fantasy</genre>
      <language>English</language>
    </book>

    <book>
      <title>A Storm of Swords</title>
      <author>George Martin</author>
      <summary>
        A Storm of Swords picks up the story where A Clash of Kings ends. The Seven Kingdoms are in the grip of the
        War of the Five Kings, with Robb Stark, Balon Greyjoy, Renly Baratheon, Joffrey Baratheon, and Stannis
        Baratheon fighting to secure their crowns, although Renly has already died. Stannis's attempt to take King's
        Landing has been defeated by the new alliance between House Lannister (backing Joffrey) and House Tyrell,
        whilst House Martell has also pledged its support to the Lannisters. Meanwhile, a large host of wildlings is
        marching on the Wall under Mance Rayder, with only the tiny force of the Night's Watch in its path, and in the
        distant east Daenerys Targaryen is on her way back to Pentos in the hope of raising forces to retake the Iron
        Throne.
      </summary>
      <isbn>0553106635</isbn>
      <genre>Epic Fantasy</genre>
      <language>English</language>
    </book>

    <book>
      <title>The Name of the Wind</title>
      <author>Patrick Rothfuss</author>
      <summary>
        This is the riveting first-person narrative of Kvothe, a young man who grows to be one of the most notorious
        magicians his world has ever seen. From his childhood in a troupe of traveling players, to years spent as a
        near-feral orphan in a crime-riddled city, to his daringly brazen yet successful bid to enter a legendary
        school of magic, The Name of the Wind is a masterpiece that transports readers into the body and mind of a
        wizard.
      </summary>
      <isbn>9780756404079</isbn>
      <genre>Heroic Fantasy</genre>
      <language>English</language>
    </book>

    <book>
      <title>The Wise Man's Fear</title>
      <author>Patrick Rothfuss</author>
      <summary>
        In The Wise Man’s Fear, Kvothe searches for answers, attempting to uncover the truth about the mysterious
        Amyr, the Chandrian, and the death of his parents. Along the way, Kvothe is put on trial by the legendary
        Adem mercenaries, forced to reclaim the honor of his family, and travels into the Fae realm. There he meets
        Felurian, the faerie woman no man can resist, and who no man has ever survived…until Kvothe. Now, Kvothe takes
        his first steps on the path of the hero and learns how difficult life can be when a man becomes a legend in
        his own time.
      </summary>
      <isbn>9780756404734</isbn>
      <genre>Heroic Fantasy</genre>
      <language>English</language>
    </book>
  </books>

  <authors>
    <author>
      <first_name>George</first_name>
      <last_name>Martin</last_name>
      <birth_date>
        <year>1948</year>
        <month>09</month>
        <day>20</day>
      </birth_date>
      <death_date>?</death_date>
    </author>

    <author>
      <first_name>Patrick</first_name>
      <last_name>Rothfuss</last_name>
      <birth_date>
        <year>1973</year>
        <month>06</month>
        <day>06</day>
      </birth_date>
      <death_date>?</death_date>
    </author>
  </authors>

  <bookinstances>
    <bookinstance>
      <book>A Dance with Dragons</book>
      <imprint>Published on July 12, 2011 by Bantam Spectra (US)</imprint>
      <due_back>?</due_back>
      <borrower>?</borrower>
    </bookinstance>

    <bookinstance>
      <book>A Game of Thrones</book>
      <imprint>Published on August 1, 1996 by Bantam Spectra (US)</imprint>
      <due_back>?</due_back>
      <borrower>?</borrower>
    </bookinstance>

    <bookinstance>
      <book>The Name of the Wind</book>
      <imprint>Published on March 27, 2007 by DAW Books Hardcover</imprint>
      <due_back>?</due_back>
      <borrower>?</borrower>
    </bookinstance>
  </bookinstances>
</local_library_data>
